[music]
[音乐]
Hello and welcome to section 6
您好，欢迎来到第6节
of lesson 2.
第二课
In this part we're going to talk about the terminal operations that are available
在这一部分中，我们将讨论可用的终端操作
in the stream interface. We've talked about where you can generate stream sources from,
在流接口中。我们已经讨论了您可以在何处生成流源，
we've talked about various intermediate operations that you can apply
我们已经讨论了可以应用的各种中间操作
in terms of the pipeline now we're going to talk about how you can have the
在管道方面，我们将讨论如何拥有
other end if your pipeline, how you can terminate
另一端，如果您的管道，如何终止
that processing and generate either explicit result
处理并产生显式结果
or some kind of side effect. so as I said,
或某种副作用。就像我说的
terminal operations are all about how we take
终端操作全都与我们的态度有关
the stream of values that we've been processing
我们一直在处理的价值流
and then terminate this pipeline operations.
然后终止此管道操作。
And I also said in terms of how this works internally,
我还谈到了内部运作方式，
its only when we get to the terminal operation
只有当我们进入终端操作时
that we actually do any real processing. At that point we'll
我们实际上进行了任何实际处理。到那时，我们将
evaluate what needs to be done internally in the library code
评估库代码内部需要执行的操作
and that way we can apply various optimizations, we can do
这样我们可以应用各种优化，我们可以
lazy evaluation we can merge, we fuse operations together where required,
我们可以合并惰性评估，在需要时将操作融合在一起，
we can eliminate redundant operations.
我们可以消除多余的操作。
I showed the example in the earlier section of the
我在前面的示例中展示了该示例
the lesson where you skip limit and we don't have to read all the lines from
在您跳过限制的课程中，我们不必阅读所有内容
the file;
文件;
we only read the number that would need to match that skip
我们只读取与该跳过匹配的数字
limit. We can also do parallel execution.
限制。我们还可以执行并行执行。
So we can identify where
这样我们可以确定在哪里
things to be done in parallel, we can apply that, again we'll talk more about
并行完成的事情，我们可以应用它，我们将再次讨论
that in lesson 3.
在第3课中
The ultimate result of a terminal operation
终端操作的最终结果
is either explicit result or some kind of side effect like printing a message.
是显式结果或某种副作用，例如打印消息。
Let's start by looking how we can match
让我们从如何匹配开始
elements because there are quite large number terminal operations that
元素，因为有大量的终端操作
are available in the standard stream API. The first of these
在标准流API中可用。这些中的第一个
is findFirst, and what this will do is it will take
是findFirst，它将要做的是
the input stream.
输入流。
The first one that matches
第一个匹配
will be the one that is returned
将是返回的那个
and that will terminate the stream. This is a a good example of how you can terminate
这将终止流。这是如何终止的一个很​​好的例子
an infinite stream,
无限的溪流
because you can simply say, Let's have an infinite stream of
因为你可以简单地说，让我们拥有无限的
random numbers and we will stop when we find the first one is greater than
随机数，当我们发现第一个大于
10 for example. There's also another form of findFirst called findAny.
以10为例。 findFirst还有另一种形式，称为findAny。
It works in very much the same way as findFirst,
它的工作方式与findFirst几乎相同，
but is for where you have parallel streams.
但适用于您有并行流的地方。
Now the reason of having findAny verse findFirst
现在找到findAny的原因findFirst
is that findAny will give you a result
是findAny会给你结果
more quickly because its non-deterministic.
更快，因为它不确定。
Any thread that matches
任何匹配的线程
will give you a result. If you want deterministic result, as in
会给你结果。如果要确定性的结果，例如
if you want to have the same result every time given the same set of
如果您希望每次给定相同的一组结果都具有相同的结果
inputs then you would need to use findFirst. findAny
输入，那么您将需要使用findFirst。 findAny
will simply return a value that matches but in a non-deterministic way
只会返回一个匹配但不确定的值
when you have parallel streams.
当您有并行流时。
There are some other ones. There's allMatch,
还有其他一些。有所有比赛，
which will ensure that all the elements on the input stream
这将确保输入流上的所有元素
match against the Predicate or not that will return a boolean,
与predicate匹配或不匹配将返回布尔值，
true if they do match the Predicate and false if they don't.
如果它们与predicate匹配，则为true；否则，则为false。
Another one anyMatch,
另一个比赛，
so if any of the elements on the input stream match the
因此，如果输入流中的任何元素与
Predicate based on predicate then it will turn true,
基于predicate的predicate将变为true，
otherwise false and the inverse of that which is noneMatch,
否则为false，与noneMatch的取反，
so that will say if none of the elements match the based on the Predicate
这样就可以说是否所有元素都不符合基于predicate的
then it will return true. There's various different ways that you can use
然后它将返回true。您可以使用多种不同的方式
to match elements that are coming from the process
匹配来自流程的元素
stream and been terminated accordingly. If you want to collect results, this is
流并因此终止。如果您想收集结果，这是
something that
一些东西
you frequently want to do and get the results into
您经常想做并获得结果
maybe a list or a map or something like that.
也许是列表或地图之类的东西。
and collect is the way to do that
收集是做到这一点的方法
What it does is it effectively performs mutable reduction
它的作用是有效执行可变减少
on the stream, so it takes the elements on the stream and puts them into
在流上，因此它将流上的元素放入其中
whatever Collector defines as the place to put them. We're gonna spend a lot more time
无论Collector定义为放置它们的地方。我们要花更多的时间
talking about this in lesson 3 so I won't go into any more detail about that now.
在第3课中讨论这一点，所以我现在不再赘述。
Similarly, if you want to create an array
同样，如果要创建数组
from the results, because that's not collections in the sense of
从结果来看，因为这不是集合
the classes then you can use toArray and
然后可以使用toArray和
that will return you an array, which contains the elements of the input stream.
这将返回一个数组，其中包含输入流的元素。
There are also many ways of achieving numerical results
还有很多方法可以得到数值结果
if you're dealing with an object stream. We'll talk about
如果要处理对象流。我们将谈论
primitive streams in a moment, but for a object stream
片刻流，但是对于对象流
you can call count. What that
您可以致电计数。那是什么
will do is simply count how many elements are there on the input stream.
要做的只是简单地计算输入流中有多少个元素。
That way if you're reading lines from a file,
这样，如果您正在从文件中读取行，
if you pass that into count it will tell you how many lines
如果您将其计算在内，它将告诉您多少行
there are in the file. There's also
在文件中。还有
max and min which will use a Comparator
最大值和最小值将使用比较器
to determine which is either the maximum value
确定哪个是最大值
or minimum value using that Comparator,
或使用该比较器的最小值，
so if you've got strings you can compare
所以如果你有琴弦可以比较
length of them using the Comparator or you could add up
使用比较器的长度，也可以加起来
the values at the individual characters and compare based on that;
各个字符的值，并据此进行比较；
whatever you want to do you can do using the Comparator
无论您想做什么，都可以使用比较器
and you can either give it maximum value or the minimum value.
您可以给它最大值或最小值。
Both these return what's called an Optional and
这两个都返回所谓的Optional和
I'll talk about that in next part of the lesson; so don't worry about that now
我将在本课程的下一部分中讨论这一点；所以现在不用担心
but it's essentially how we deal with things
但这实质上是我们处理事物的方式
if there are no elements on the input stream what do we return.
如果输入流上没有元素，我们将返回什么。
For primitive type streams, so the intStream, DoubleStream and
对于原始类型的流，因此intStream，DoubleStream和
LongStream there's a couple of other numerical
LongStream还有一些其他数值
terminal operations that we can use. One of those is average,
我们可以使用的终端操作。其中之一是平均水平，
so that will return the arithmetic mean of the
这样就可以返回
stream. We've got numbers, add them up, divide by the
流。我们有数字，将它们加起来，除以
number of elements in the stream and that's what we get. That also returns an Optional.
流中元素的数量，这就是我们得到的。这还会返回一个Optional。
We'll talk about that next part of the lesson. sum
我们将在本课程的下一部分中讨论。和
returns the sum all the elements in stream and
返回流中所有元素的和
that doesn't return Optional; if there are no elements on the input stream
没有返回Optional；如果输入流上没有元素
it will return zero.
它将返回零。
Iteration. We've already seen that the
迭代。我们已经看到
a Iterable interface now has forEach
一个可迭代的接口现在具有forEach
method on it, but we can use that
方法，但是我们可以使用它
in terms of a stream as well. So we can say
在流方面也是如此。所以我们可以说
that for stream we can do forEach and have a consumer
对于流，我们可以做到forEach，并拥有一个消费者
process whatever the elements on the input stream are.
处理输入流上的任何元素。
So we'll just repeat that for each element on the input stream.
因此，我们将对输入流中的每个元素重复此操作。
There's also one that's kind of related to that which is forEachOrdered.
还有一种与forEachOrdered相关。
So that's very much like forEach,
所以非常像forEach
but again this is when you deal with parallel streams
但这又是当您处理并行流时
and if you want to ensure that the
如果您要确保
ordering is the same then forEachOrdered will do that.
排序是相同的，然后forEachOrdered将执行该操作。
It will guarantee that the same set of input elements
它将确保输入元素相同
you get the same order of output elements.
您将获得相同顺序的输出元素。
forEach won't necessarily do that if you have a parallel stream because there's non-determinism
如果您有并行流，forEach不一定会那样做，因为存在不确定性
involved in that. forEachOrdered will make sure that the order is the same.
参与其中。 forEachOrdered将确保顺序相同。
Be careful when you use these.
使用它们时要小心。
There are definitely places where they can be used very effectively,
肯定有一些地方可以非常有效地使用它们，
but you tend to,
但是你倾向于
as we'll talk about in week 3 in the third lesson there are some situations where
正如我们将在第三课的第三周中讨论的那样，在某些情况下
you may be tempted to use these
您可能会想使用这些
because you're still thinking in an imperative style. We'll
因为您仍在以命令式的方式思考。好
deal with that in week 3. Folding a stream.
在第3周中处理该问题。
This is where what we want to do is take a input stream has multiple elements
这是我们想要做的就是输入流中包含多个元素
on it
在上面
and we want to reduce it to a single value.
并且我们希望将其减少为单个值。
Now we can do that, as you've already seen using something like
现在我们可以做到，因为您已经看到使用类似
count that will count how many elements there are on the input stream.
计算将计算输入流中有多少个元素。
We can do things like sum, which will add up all the values
我们可以做诸如sum之类的事情，它将所有值相加
on the input stream, but reduce is a more
在输入流上，但减少是更多
general purpose way of doing that
通用方法
and this is much more the sort of functional approach to programming.
这更是一种编程的函数方法。
So what we do with the reduced method
那么我们用简化方法做什么
is we use BinaryOperator and
我们使用BinaryOperator和
remember back to the function package, BinaryOperator
记得回到函数包BinaryOperator
is like a function but takes
就像一个函数，但需要
two input parameters
两个输入参数
and returns a type, all which are the same and
并返回一个相同的类型
we call that the accumulator. What the accumulator does is it takes
我们称之为累加器。累加器要做的是
a partial results on the next element in the stream
流中下一个元素的部分结果
and returns a new partial result. So that's why the
并返回新的部分结果。这就是为什么
a the types are all the same because it will
类型都是一样的，因为它将
turn a partial result  which is one element that
转一个部分结果是一个元素
is whatever is the of a result so far,
到目前为止的结果是什么，
take the next element on the stream apply the accumulator to that and
将流中的下一个元素应用于累加器并
return a new partial result, which will be used the next time
返回一个新的部分结果，将在下次使用
when we process next element in the stream. Again, we're spend more time
当我们处理流中的下一个元素时。同样，我们花更多的时间
in week 3 talking about how to use the reduce operator
在第3周中讨论如何使用reduce运算符
and reduce method in different situations.
并减少不同情况下的方法。
So we'll talk about that in more detail then. This also returns an Optional
因此，我们将在后面详细讨论。这也返回一个可选
again, we'll talk about that next part and then there are
再次，我们将讨论下一部分，然后有
two other slight variations on this.
在这方面还有其他两个细微变化。
One which takes an initial value and that doesn't return an
一个具有初始值且不返回
Optional because there's an initial values so if there are no elements on the input stream
可选，因为有一个初始值，所以如果输入流上没有元素
then you can just return the initial value
那么你就可以返回初始值
There's one which also takes an initial value and a BiFunction,
还有一个也带有初始值和BiFunction，
which is really equivalent to doing a map
这真的等效于绘制地图
and then a reduction. so its equivalent to
然后减少。所以相当于
doing the map using the BiFunction and then doing the reduction using the
使用BiFunction绘制地图，然后使用
initial value and the accumulator.
初始值和累加器。
To summarize section 6 then...
要总结第6节，那么...
A terminal operation will provide
终端操作将提供
either an explicit result or side effect
明确的结果或副作用
and a side effect could be something like using the forEach terminal operation
副作用可能类似于使用forEach终端操作
and printing out the values of the stream. So that doesn't generate a
并打印出流的值。因此不会产生
specific result but
具体结果但是
does something with the
与
input stream. They are many types of
输入流。他们有很多类型
operation available, and we need to look at some of these in
操作可用，我们需要看看其中的一些
more detail and we'll do that in week 3, so we'll look at
更多细节，我们将在第3周进行介绍，因此我们来看一下
reductions, we'll look at collectors in more detail
减少量，我们将更详细地研究收集器
when we get to lesson 3. And that
当我们上第三课时
is the end of section 6.
在第6节的末尾。